THAO TRUONG (SCARLETT)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Vancouver, BC 778-917-8078 scarlett.truong307@gmail.com https://thao.netlify.app/

PROFILE

Experienced and fast-learning Software Engineer with 5+ years in the software development field, specialized in React.

SKILLS

Front-end JavaScript (React, React Native Redux, Hooks, d3), TypeScript, Wordpress

SASS, Styled-components, Material UI, Tailwind, Figma CMS (Strapi), Google Tag Manager, RudderStack, FullStory

Nextjs, Jest, Vercel, Netlify

Back-end NodeJS, Express, Java, Python, SocketIO, Unit test (Jest, Mocha)

Database PostgreSQL, TimescaleDB, MongoDB, Firebase, InfluxDB

Infrastructure CICD (Github actions, Jenkin, Apollo), Docker

AWS (EC2, S3, ECR, ECS, RDS, Lambda, Secret Manager, Cloudwatch)

Management Agile, Jira, BitBucket, Git, Slack, Teams

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2022 -Jul 2023

WEB ENGINEER

Binance.US

- Developed and maintained 14 web application projects in React/Redux.
- Implemented performance optimizations by server-side caching to enhance website speed and responsiveness.
- Worked closely with designers to develop new design system with reusable UI components and libraries.
- Led in some revamp projects and provided technical guidance, code reviews, and mentoring.
- Implemented more animations using framer-motion to increase visual appealing and user experience.
- Providing mentoring to 3-4 junior developers and interns.
- Collaborated with designers, backends, QAs and devops in multiple projects to deliver final products.
- Conducted informative Github Pull Request reviews for 13 developers.

Apr 2022 -

FULL STACK REACT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Oct 2022

Panago Pizza Inc.

- Developed and maintained company website in WordPress, iOS and Android mobile application in React Native.
- Customised back-end code in Ruby for special promotions and events.
- Maintained company third-party delivery apps (Doordash, Uber, Skipp the Dishes) written in JavaScript.
- Consulted in building a new hybrid platform for store management using Flutter.

Oct 2018 -Apr 2022

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DMG Blockchain Solutions

- Integrated front-end code with back-end systems and APIs to enable seamless data exchange using Node and React.
- Designed UI/UX for 2 projects using Figma
- Visualised time-series data with more than 250,000+ data entries using d3 and ApexChart
- Wrote unit tests, maintained test coverage at 70%
- Improved product's performance and scalability to handle data of over 10,000+ individual miners.
- Automated scheduling tasks by using AWS Lambda, pg_cron
- Involved in data architecture redesign and optimization
- Created proper CICD workflows with Github actions to support agile development (constant production deployments), and reduce manual developer efforts during product deployment

Jan 2019 -

WEB DEVELOPER

Sep 2018

Old Dog Web Strategies

- Built SEO report dashboard in Google Data Studio.
- Built an automation application to pull data from different APIs to generate reports and upload to Google Drive.
- Developed customers database in MongoDB

EDUCATION

2017 - 2019

POST-BACCALAUREATE DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER AND INFORMATION SYSTEM

Douglas College - 3.89/4 GPA

Award: International Student Award - Tier 1

One of group mobile project had been chosen to be presented at BC Tech

Summit Event 2019

2010 - 2014

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

University of Economics HCMC - 8.32/10 GPA

Award: Recipient of top 50 students for University Scholarship